A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of Humanities and the Arts, Office of the Vice President, Office Files of Wilson McNeil Lowry FA582
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Programs, 1952-1971; IV
  - ITR -- International Legal Studies (2 of 2), May 31, 1963 - Dec 29, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - ITR -- English as a Second Language (1 of 3), 1963 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - ITR -- English as a Second Language (2 of 3), 1964 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - ITR -- English as a Second Language (3 of 3), Mar 24, 1965 - Sep 1, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - ITR -- General, Aug 16, 1962 - Jul 26, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - ITR -- Undergraduate Education, Feb 28 - Dec 23, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - ITR -- "Non-Western Studies and Undergraduate Education" by George M Beckmann, Oct 1962 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - ITR -- Report on Non-Western Studies at Earlham and Antioch Colleges and Additional Note, Dec 1962 - Jan 1963 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - ITR -- Report on Non-Western Studies at Earlham and Antioch Colleges, Dec 8, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - ITR -- "Non-Western Studies: The Connecticut Valley Group", Dec 12, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - ITR -- Language and Linguistics -- General, Dec 5-12, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - ITR -- "Non-Western Studies: The Limits of Faculty Re-Training and Some Suggestions", Dec 14, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - ITR -- Grant Request Items, Feb 11, 1964 - May 17, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - ITR -- "Review of The Ford Foundation's International Legal Studies Program", Mar 1964 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - ITR -- Language and Linguistics -- "A Survey of Intensive Programs in the Uncommon Languages" by Roy Andrew Miller, Aug - Sep 1964 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - ITR -- Language and Linguistics -- Indiana Second Annual Report, Aug 1964 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - ITR -- Center for Applied Linguistics, Nov 16, 1964 - Aug 10, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - ITR -- American Universities Field Studies, Jan 25, 1965 - Aug 9, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - ITR -- Language and Linguistics Grant Requests, Jun 3, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - ITR -- South Africa -- Memoranda -- Foundation Policies and Work, Jul 22 - Aug 5, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - ITR -- Proposed International Legal Studies Agency, Nov 1965 - May 10, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Overseas Development (OD) -- "Report of Meeting on University Projects Under Ford Foundation Grants in South and South East Asia", Dec 7, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - OD -- South and Southeast Asia -- Evaluations and Miscellaneous Reports, Dec 7, 1959 - Apr 8, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - OD -- "Review of Ford Foundation Program in Israel and Turkey" by Benson E. Ginsburg, May 31, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - OD -- South and Southeast Asia -- Harvard-Pakistan Planning Commission Project, Mar - Aug 1962 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - OD -- General, Jun 14, 1962 - Aug 12, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - OD -- Administration, Jul 16, 1962 - Aug 31, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - OD -- Ad Hoc Trustee Committee on OD Program -- Meeting Materials, Aug 23, 1962 - Mar 29, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - OD -- Ad Hoc Trustee Committee on Personnel for Overseas Assignments, Aug 23, 1962 - Mar 5, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - OD -- Personnel for Overseas/International Development Reports, Sep 6, 1962 - Dec 4, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - OD -- Overseas Development, South and Southeast Asia, Review of 1962 and Projection of 1963, Dec 11, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - OD -- "Personnel for Overseas Development", Dec 15, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - OD -- "Notes on Bethuel M. Webster's Trip to New Delhi, Calcutta, Karachi, Beirut", Jan 21 - Feb 5, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - OD -- Latin America and Caribbean -- General, Feb 27, 1963 - Oct 10, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - OD -- "Report of the Trustees Ad Hoc Committee on the Overseas Development Program", Mar 1963 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - OD -- "Meeting of Representatives, South and Southeast Asia Program, New Delhi, February 15-16, 1963", Mar 22, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - OD -- "Evaluation of Experience in Overseas Programs, South and Southeast Asia", May 17 - Sep 17, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - OD -- Middle East & Africa -- General, Summer 1963 - Aug 9, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - OD -- South and Southeast Asia -- General, Nov 11, 1963 - Oct 19, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - OD -- South and Southeast Asia Program Fiscal Year Reports, Dec 9, 1963 - Dec 30, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - OD -- Grant Lists, Oct 30, 1964 - Sep 21, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - OD -- Aid Technical Assistance Questionnaire, Nov 1964 - Feb 3, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - OD -- "Reflections on the Foundation's Experience in Overseas Development" by F. C. Ward, Nov 29, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - OD -- "The Political Situation in the Dominican Republic" by Robert A. Mayer, Sep 10, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - OD -- South and Southeast Asia -- New Delhi Office Building, Jan 13, 1966 - Jan 18, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - OD -- Agriculture Reports and Outline by F. F. Hill and Related Memoranda, Feb 8, 1966 - Apr 27, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - OD -- Reviews of Overseas Development Program, Mar 14 - Aug 8, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Public Affairs (PA) -- University of Wisconsin, Madison Report, Jan 13, 1960 - Feb 11, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - PA -- Southeastern Michigan Metropolitan Community Research Corporation and PENJERDEL, Oct 30, 1961 - Jan 10, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - PA -- Youth Studies Center -- Reports of Visits, Nov 20, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - PA -- General Correspondence and Memoranda, Jan 16, 1962 - Aug 23, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - PA -- University of Wisconsin, Milwaukee Report Re: University Projects and Proposals, Jan 23, 1962 -Jan 24, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - PA -- Urban Transportation -- Rand Corporation -- Reports, Memoranda, Jul 31, 1962 - May 1963 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - PA -- MIT & Harvard Joint Center for Urban Studies, Oct 3, 1962 - Sep 1, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - PA -- Urban Extension Program at University of Illinois, Nov 1962 - Jan 3, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - PA -- University of Wisconsin Fox Valley Report Notes, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - PA -- "Gray Areas" Projects Reviews, Jan 10, 1963 - Aug 13, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - PA -- Urban Extension Program at Rutgers University, May 1963 - Apr 20, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - PA -- Transportation and Traffic Safety -- General, Aug 6, 1963 - Oct 13, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - PA -- Transcript of Notes from Urban Extension Conference (10/27-29/1963), Oct 1963-1964 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - PA -- Urban Extension Program at University of California, Nov 22, 1963 - Feb 17, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - PA -- Urban Extension Program -- General, Dec 10, 1963 - Mar 28, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - PA -- University of Wisconsin, Columbia County Report Memo, Jan 15, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - PA -- John F Kennedy Library and Institute, Jan 22, 1964 - Sep 7, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - PA -- "The Public Affairs Program, Law Schools and the Administration of Justice" by William Pincus, Feb 11, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - PA -- Urban Extension/ACTION Housing -- Memoranda and Report, Feb 20 - Apr 15, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - PA -- Urban Extension ACTION-Housing Report, Mar 31, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - PA -- "University of Wisconsin Urban Extension Program" by Richard C. Sheldon, Apr 1964 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - PA -- Report on University of Oklahoma Urban Science Program, May 1964 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - PA -- "Review of the Urban Extension Program", May 11, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - PA -- Kansas City Association of Trusts and Foundations -- Memoranda Re: Grants, Jul 20 - Nov 17, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - PA -- MIT & Harvard Joint Center for Urban Studies -- Reports, Fall 1964 - Mar 25, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - PA -- Los Angeles Watts Riots -- General (1 of 2), 1965 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - PA -- Los Angeles Watts Riots -- General (2 of 2), 1966 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - PA -- Oakland Gray Areas Project, Feb 2 - Aug 9, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - PA -- New Haven Gray Areas Project, Apr 8, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - PA -- Education and World Affairs Proposal Memoranda and Program Report, Apr 12, 1965 - Feb 21, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - PA -- Los Angeles Watts Riots -- McCone Commission, Aug 31, 1965 - Mar 1, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - PA -- Report Re: Los Angeles Watts Riots by Malcolm Moos, Sep 14, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - PA -- Los Angeles Watts Riots -- News Reports, Oct 14, 1965 - May 22, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - PA - Citizens Crusade Against Poverty -- Memoranda, Jan 7 - Feb 1, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - PA -- Los Angeles Watts Riots -- Grant Requests, Mar 21 - Mar 28, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Policy and Planning (P&P) -- Teacher Education (1 of 4), Fall 1954 - Mar 1963 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - P&P -- Teacher Education (2 of 4), Jan 28 - Oct 1965 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - P&P -- Teacher Education (3 of 4), Dec 1 - Dec 31, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - P&P -- Teacher Education (4 of 4), Feb 13 - Apr 7, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - P&P -- Behavioral Sciences Program Final Report, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - P&P -- Behavioral and Social Sciences -- General, 1957 - 1966 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - P&P -- Berlin Program Evaluation Dry Run, Apr 14, 1959 - Oct 22, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - P&P -- Evaluation Reports, Jul 17, 1959 - Jul 1965 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - P&P -- The Brookings Institution -- Institutional Work and FF Grants, Jan 28, 1960 - Nov 8, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - P&P -- "Report on Urban Studies Program at the University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill", Apr 27, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - P&P -- Henry T. Heald/Wilson McNeil Lowry Memoranda, Jan 14, 1961 - May 4, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - P&P -- Behavioral and Social Sciences -- Reports and Supporting Materials, 1962 - 1963 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - P&P -- Behavioral and Social Sciences -- University of Rochester -- FF Grants, 1962 - 1966 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - P&P -- Grant Records, 1962 - 1966 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - P&P -- "An Evaluation of The Ford Foundation Grants to California, Chicago, Columbia, Harvard, Princeton and Yale Universities to Establish Rotating Research Professorships in American Governmental Affairs" by Marion Clawson, Feb 1962 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - P&P -- Program Planning Budget, Jun 11, 1962 - Jun 8, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - P&P -- Staff Miscellaneous, Jun 20, 1962 - Nov 1, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - P&P -- Appropriation for Planning and Evaluation Studies, Oct 12, 1962 - Dec 23, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - P&P -- Civil Rights and Inter-Group Relations Proposals and Ideas, Nov 6, 1962 - Aug 23, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - P&P -- Approved Administrative Budgets, 1963 - 1966 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - P&P -- Travel and Study Awards -- General Correspondence and Memoranda (1 of 2), 1963 - 1964 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - P&P -- Travel and Study Awards -- General Correspondence and Memoranda (2 of 2), 1965 - 1966 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - P&P -- The Greater Cleveland Associated Foundation -- Appointment Schedules and Background Materials, 1963 - 1965 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - P&P -- Miscellaneous -- Memoranda Re: Travel, etc., Feb 15, 1963 - Sep 13, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - P&P -- Evaluation of Gray Areas -- General, May 7, 1963 - Jul 6, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - P&P - Articles on the Ford Foundation, May 15, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - P&P -- Evaluation of Gray Areas Project -- New Haven, Jul 14, 1963 - Apr 8, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - P&P -- Year End Program Planning Budget Modifications and Memoranda, Jul 24 - Sep 23, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - P&P -- "New Ideas for Cities as Learned from Foundation Grants" by Paul N. Ylvisaker, Aug 12, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - P&P -- Negro Education -- General, Sep 11, 1963 - Aug 3, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - P&P -- Center for Advanced Studies in the Behavioral Sciences, Oct 1, 1963 - Feb 17, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - P&P -- "Historic and Architectural Preservation and Restoration" -- Discussion Paper and Memorandum, Dec 1963 - Jun 7, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - P&P -- "The Educational and Other Development of the Negro" Discussion Paper, Dec 6, 1963 - Aug 20, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - P&P -- University of Wisconsin Evaluation -- General, Dec 6, 1963 - Jul 27, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - P&P -- Basic Policy Planning, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - P&P -- Evaluations of Foundation Programs, 1964 - 1965 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - P&P -- Stanford University Evaluation, Reports, Articles, Miscellaneous, 1964 - 1966 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - P&P -- Institute of International Education (IIE) Evaluation Correspondence, Feb 12, 1964 - Feb 8, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - P&P -- Discussion Papers and Evaluations, Board Meetings/Progress Reports, Apr 24, 1964 - Jun 22, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - P&P -- Evaluation of Gray Areas Projects -- Oakland, Jul 1, 1964 - Jul 27, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - P&P -- President's Staff Meeting -- Memoranda, Jul 6, 1964 - Jul 12, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - P&P -- "Support of Regranting Activities" -- Report, Correspondence and Memoranda, Aug 19 - Sep 21, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - P&P -- Endowment Grants Memoranda, Sep 11, 1964 - Sep 16, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - P&P -- P&P Analyses (Malcolm Moos, R.C. Sheldon, E.S. Staples), Oct 15 - Oct 22, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - P&P -- Academic Exchanges with the Soviet Union and Eastern Europe -- Evaluation Dry Run, Oct 16, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - P&P -- Foreign Policy Association -- Evaluation Dry Run, Oct 16 - Oct 22, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - P&P -- Henry T. Heald Observations on P&P Inventories, Dec 1964 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - P&P -- Teacher Education Evaluation -- Consultants and Miscellaneous Reports and Notes (1 of 2), Dec 5, 1964 - Oct 8, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - P&P -- Teacher Education Evaluation -- Consultants and Miscellaneous Reports and Notes (2 of 2), Nov 8, 1965 - Mar 1, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - P&P -- Agenda for Discussion of Planning Questions, Dec 15, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - P&P -- Washington Follow-Up on Vice President's Meeting, Dec 15, 1964 - Jun 1965 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - P&P -- Compensation and Benefits Study Committee, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - P&P -- Institute of International Education (IIE) Evaluation Supporting Materials (1 of 2), 1965 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - P&P -- Institute of International Education (IIE) Evaluation Supporting Materials (2 of 2), 1965 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - P&P -- Negro Education Background Material, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - P&P -- Stanford University Evaluation, 1965 - 1966 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - P&P -- Teacher Education Evaluation -- General Correspondence (1 of 2), 1965 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - P&P -- Teacher Education Evaluation -- General Correspondence (2 of 2), 1966 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - P&P -- Washington Correspondence (with Senate, White House, etc.), 1965 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - P&P -- Washington Interview Memoranda, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - P&P -- Washington Miscellaneous -- Memoranda on Government Meetings, etc., 1965 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - P&P -- Washington -- Treasury Report on Tax-Exempt Foundations, 1965 - 1969 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - P&P -- "Some Policy Considerations of Endowment Grants", Jan 15, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - P&P -- Ford Foundation Programs Developing Federal Activities, Feb 15, 1965 - Jan 26, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - P&P -- Manpower Planning and Development, Feb 12 - Nov 3, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - P&P -- "The Ford Foundation Programs and Developing Federal Activities" Report Discussed at Officers and Directors Meeting (5/7/1965), Feb 23, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - P&P -- Vice President's Meeting, Washington (4/7/1965) -- Meeting Materials, Mar 11 - Apr 7, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - P&P -- Teacher Education Evaluation Interviews (1 of 3), Mar 18 - Nov 8, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - P&P -- Teacher Education Evaluation Interviews (2 of 3), Nov 8 - Dec 20, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - P&P -- Teacher Education Evaluation Interviews (3 of 3), Jan 25 - Mar 31, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - P&P -- Washington Files -- Policy and Planning Questions, Mar 30, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - P&P -- Policy and Planning Questions -- Meetings with Domestic Programs, Mar 30 - Jun 11, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - P&P -- Policy and Planning Questions -- Meetings with International Programs, Mar 30 - Jun 10, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - P&P -- Negro Education Conversation Memoranda, Apr 9, 1965 - Jul 26, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - P&P -- Information Coordinating Unit -- Memoranda Re: Possible Establishment of Unit, Apr 23 - May 14, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - P&P -- Policy and Planning Assignments, May 17 - Nov 14, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - P&P -- Institute of International Education (IIE) Evaluation Interview Memoranda, Aug 4, 1965 - Mar 18, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - P&P -- The Greater Cleveland Foundation Evaluation Correspondence, Oct 6, 1965 - Feb 4, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - P&P -- Education Budget Memoranda, Apr 29, 1965 - Feb 15, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - P&P -- Teacher Education Evaluation Meetings, Jun 9, 1965 - Jan 21, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - P&P -- The Ford Foundation/Jackson State College Conference, Jul 6 - Aug 10, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - P&P -- Educational and Other Development of the Negro Memorandum, Aug 4, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - P&P -- Automotive Safety Study, Aug 6, 1965 - Mar 1, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - P&P -- "The Ford Foundation Programs and Developing Federal Activities", Sep 1965 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - P&P -- "The Ford Foundation Training Associate Program", Oct 1965 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - P&P -- Ford Foundation Statement for Proposed New York State Law on Regulation of Charitable Corporations, Dec 27, 1965 - Jan 21, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - P&P -- Proposed State Registration of Foundations, Dec 27, 1965 - Jan 21, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - P&P -- Drug Addiction -- Correspondence, Memoranda, Report, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - P&P -- Ford Foundation's Future Income and Asset Projections, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - P&P -- Graduate Education -- Correspondence (1 of 2), 1966 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - P&P -- Graduate Education -- Correspondence (2 of 2), 1966 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - P&P -- Graduate Education -- General -- Staff Memoranda, Statistics, Reports (1 of 2), 1966 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - P&P -- Graduate Education -- General -- Staff Memoranda, Statistics, Reports (2 of 2), 1966 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - P&P -- Graduate Education University Memoranda (1 of 2), 1966 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - P&P -- Graduate Education University Memoranda (2 of 2), 1966 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - P&P -- The Greater Cleveland Associated Foundation Evaluation Report, Jan 1966 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - P&P -- Report of Foundation Salary and Benefits Policies, Jan 1966 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - P&P -- American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS) Sessions at Berkeley, Jan 5 - Jan 6, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - P&P -- Science and Engineering Budget Memoranda, Jan 25, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - P&P -- Special Programs Budget Memoranda, Jan 28 - Feb 16, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - P&P -- Teacher Education Evaluation Notes, Jan 28 - Mar 1, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - P&P -- Ford Foundation and the Press, Feb 9 - Feb 21, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - P&P -- Population Budget Memoranda, Feb 9 - Feb 23, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - P&P -- Program Planning Budget Memoranda, Feb 10 - Mar 24, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - P&P -- International Affairs Budget Memoranda, Feb 24 - Mar 16, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - P&P -- Minority Group Problems Committee -- General -- Memoranda, May 18 - Sep 27, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - P&P -- Possible PhD Program General Memoranda, May 20 - Nov 29, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - P&P -- Columbia University General Campaign, May 23 - Jun 28, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - P&P -- "The Negro and the Ford Foundation" by Calvin Kytle (Consultant) and General Correspondence, May 23 - Aug 8, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - P&P -- Henry Ford Memorial Museum Evaluation, May 27, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - P&P -- National Commission on Drug Dependency -- General -- Memoranda, Jun 15 - Jun 23, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - P&P -- Graduate Education Interview Notes, Jun 17 - Jul 11, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - P&P -- Graduate Education Memoranda, Jun 21 - Jun 29, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - P&P -- Graduate Education Miscellaneous Memoranda, Jun 23 - Aug 5, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - P&P -- Graduate Education Study -- General -- Memoranda and Correspondence, Jul 3 - Aug 24, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - P&P -- Possible PhD Program Guidelines, Jul 10 - Aug 5, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - P&P -- New Titles and Assignments for Ford Foundation Professional Staff, Dec 22, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Population (POP) -- General -- Memoranda Re: Population Program, Dec 15, 1952 - May 25, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - POP -- Population Council Data, Jan 25, 1962 - Sep 24, 1964 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - POP -- International Planned Parenthood Federation -- Memoranda, Proposals Re: Foundation Grants, Jun 8, 1962 - Mar 1, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - POP -- Miscellaneous Reports Re: Population Problems, Foundation Work, Family Planning Programs, Birth Control, etc., Dec 11, 1962 - Oct 30, 1964 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - POP -- Policy/Position Papers, Jan 23 - Mar 29, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Science and Engineering (SE) -- General -- Memoranda, Background on Science and Engineering Program, Nov 9, 1960 - Apr 5, 1966 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - SE -- Conservation -- Memoranda and Report Re: Resources and the Environment, Aug 29, 1962 - Jan 15, 1966 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - SE -- Resources for the Future Reports, Feb 1963 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - SE -- Resources for the Future Correspondence, Mar 8, 1963 - Jun 3, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Special Projects (SPE) -- Special Program in Education -- Memoranda Re: Foundation Grants, Sep 8, 1959 - Nov 6, 1964 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - SPE -- General -- Memoranda Re: Foundation Grants, May 3, 1963 - May 17, 1966 (Box 25, Folder 6)
- Speeches and Writings, 1955-1974; V
  These files consist of transcripts, speeches, speaking notes, and published and unpublished articles by Mr. Lowry on the subjects of education and the arts. Of note is Mr. Lowry’s testimony on three occasions before the House Select Subcommittee on Education. There is also a single speech by Paul Ylvisaker, another Ford Foundation employee, on urbanization.
  Files are arranged by person and then chronologically by date of speech, interview or publication.
  - General -- Index, Press Release, 1964-1970 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Studio Area Theatre Conference Speech Reel, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - "Handicaps to the Press's Contribution to Increasing Communication Among Peoples," UNESCO 5th National Conference, Cincinnati, OH, Nov 3 - Nov 5, 1955 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - "The Humanities and the Private Colleges," Meeting of the Federation of Illinois Colleges, Blackburn College, Carlinville, IL, 1957 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - "Higher Education and the Individual," Louisiana College Conference, Alexandria, LA, Mar 1, 1957 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - "Institutional Cooperation in Higher Education," Midwest Conference on Graduate Study and Research, Chicago, IL, Apr 1, 1957 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - "Role of the Foundation in American Society," The Nassau Club, Princeton, NJ, Apr 16, 1958 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - "Economics of the Arts in America," Voice of America Forum Lectures (published lecture), Spring 1960 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - "Patronage of the Arts: The United States," Congress for Cultural Freedom, West Berlin, Germany, Jun 21, 1960 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - "Music and the Ford Foundation," Music Journal (published article), Apr 1961 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Talk on FF Program in Humanities and the Arts, American Federation of Arts Convention, Chicago, IL, Apr 14, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - "Ford Foundation and the Theatre," Equity Magazine (published article), May 1961 (Box 26, Folder 12)